## Aleksei Miliutin Head of Product

Georgia, Batumi · 995 511 259 374 · milyutin.an@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/anmilyutin

#### **SUMMARY**

Head of Product with over 15 years of experience in IT, has experience in rebuilding the entire logistics of a company from scratch, creating a flexible logistics platform. Effectively managed 6 product teams, reducing the company's logistics costs by almost RUB 1bn per year, achieving an ROI of 8.5. Launched a restaurant delivery service, connecting 35,000 restaurants in 360 Russian cities and an on-demand delivery service from supermarkets, generating over 40% GMV.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Head of Product**

Aug 2022 - to present

## Kuper, Georgia, Batumi

Is the leader of the Russian market among e-grocery marketplaces in 2021, 2022 and 2023, with a GMV of over two billion dollars.

- Effectively managed 6 product teams, reducing the company's logistics costs by almost RUB 1bn a year, achieving an ROI of 8.5.
- Launched a restaurant delivery service, connecting 35,000 restaurants in 360 cities across Russia, expanding the geography of services provided.
- Turned the company's economy into positive contribution profit 1 (+34p vs -140p (June 2024)).
- Launched a pilot of the "Delivery by Click" project together with Samokat, the "Multi-retailer Basket" project together with Samokat and MegaMarket, increasing convenience for users and increasing the number of orders.
- Developed a logistics platform, providing a flexible balance between customer service quality and economic efficiency, with quick connection of new business lines.
- Launched a new Delivery-as-a-Service (b2b) business line with positive unit economics at the start, ensuring revenue growth.

### **Senior Product Manager**

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

- Launched a fast delivery service (on-demand) from supermarkets, generating over 40% GMV.
- Designed and launched a "Shift Service" product using ML to optimise the number of couriers in a given area, reducing over-deployment of couriers by a factor of three.
- Designed and successfully launched an order dispatching system for fast delivery from scratch, improving operational efficiency.
- Designed and defended product strategy in a microservice paradigm at an architecture committee, ensuring systems modernisation and scalability.

# **Head of the Competence Centre**

Feb 2020 - Jul 2021

# Rosgosstrakh, Russian

Is the oldest insurance company in Russia, with over a century of existence. The company's annual insurance premiums amount to 1.8 billion dollars.

- Managed the company's competence center with 60+ employees, leading the successful migration of all CASCO products to the Guidewire Policy Center system.
- Supervised the migration of all company systems to AIS RAMI 2.0, coordinating 7 integration systems and 10 technical teams, ensuring 100% production rollout.

# Technical Project Manager

Jun 2016 - Jan 2020

# Rosgosstrakh, Russian

- Led a team of 20+ internal specialists and 10+ contractors (EPAM), building a centralized auto insurance sales system that generated over 80% of the company's revenue.
- Launched electronic MTPL insurance across multiple channels, including the company's website, offices, and 40+ partners, expanding market reach and competitiveness.
- Implemented a scanning and recognition system with ABBYY FlexiCapture, processing over 5 million contracts monthly.
- Established a Federal Operations Centre in Kirov, achieving an ROI of over 1 billion roubles in under four years.

#### **EDUCATION**

N.E. Bauman Moscow State Technical University, IU-6 Computer Systems and Networks, Russian, 2005

## **CERTIFICATES**

- GoPractice, Simulator for Learning Data-Driven Product Management and Growth, 2021
- University of Michigan, Introduction to Data Science in Python, 2020

- University of Michigan, Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python, 2020
- University of Alberta, Specialization: Software Product Management, 2020

# **LANGUAGES**

Russian: Native, English: B2.

## **SKILLS**

Product Strategies, Product Development, Product Vision, User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI), Product Road Mapping, Customer Experience, Agile, Scrum, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Teamwork, A/B Testing, Analytical Skills, Technology Solutions, Workable Solutions, CI/CD, Data-Driven Design, Python, SQL.